[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
[intense music]
[musik yang intens]
[Tapping sound]
[Mengetuk suara]
[rustling sound]
[suara gemerisik]
[Sound of tearing]
[Suara robek]
[Rough fighting sounds]
[Suara pertarungan yang kasar]
[Yeonwoo’s sound of encouragement]
[Suara penyemangat Yeonwoo]
[Yeonwoo’s heavy breathing]
[Nafas Yeonwoo yang berat]
[ringing footsteps]
[dering langkah kaki]
[Urgent music]
[Musik yang mendesak]
[Engine acceleration sound]
[Suara akselerasi mesin]
[tire rubbing sound]
[suara gesekan ban]
[groans with difficulty]
[mengerang dengan susah payah]
[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
[Heavy breathing] [Sound of approaching footsteps]
[Nafas berat] [Suara langkah kaki mendekat]
[Music that heightens tension]
[Musik yang meningkatkan ketegangan]
- (Yeonwoo) Haejun! - (Little Haejun) Dad!
- (Yeonwoo) Haejun! - (Haejun Kecil) Ayah!
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
(Middle-aged Yeonwoo) Father
(Yeonwoo paruh baya) Ayah
Does this mean our Haejun will come back?
Apakah ini berarti Haejun kita akan kembali?
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
I'll be nice to you when I'm there Now come...
Aku akan bersikap baik padamu saat aku di sana Sekarang datang...
Like such a fool Just waiting
Seperti orang bodoh Hanya menunggu
Will you come back, my son?
Maukah kamu kembali, anakku?
(Yeonwoo) You really irritate me, Mr.
(Yeonwoo) Anda benar-benar membuatku kesal, Tuan.
[Heavy breathing]
[Nafas berat]
[Yeonwoo’s heavy breathing]
[Nafas Yeonwoo yang berat]
[nervous music] [groan]
[musik gugup] [mengerang]
What the hell are you? uh?
Kamu ini apa? eh?
대체 뭐냐고, 새끼야
대체 뭐냐고, 새끼야
[힘겨운 신음]
[힘겨운 신음]
어? Why did you come to me?
ya? Mengapa kamu datang kepadaku?
You said you were going to catch me, huh?
Kamu bilang kamu akan menangkapku, ya?
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
(Misook) The teacher appeared on the news. [Dark sound effect]
(Misook) Guru muncul di berita. [Efek suara gelap]
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
I saw the criminal's face
Saya melihat wajah penjahat itu
Is it true?
Apakah itu benar?
I came to your house during the day too.
Aku datang ke rumahmu pada siang hari juga.
Anyway, my plan was already ruined.
Lagi pula, rencanaku sudah hancur.
I heard you wanted to hear that
Saya mendengar Anda ingin mendengarnya
Just thought I'd let you know
Kupikir aku akan memberitahumu
But you weren't there and there was someone else?
Tapi kamu tidak ada di sana dan ada orang lain?
That's also the culprit
Itu juga pelakunya
What?
Apa?
(Misuk) Originally, I went to a nearby place Although it's easier to miss
(Misuk) Awalnya, saya pergi ke tempat terdekat Meskipun lebih mudah untuk dilewatkan
Bring it into your house You came to me and wandered around
Bawa ke rumahmu Anda datang kepada saya dan berkeliaran
What are you asking me to do?
Apa yang kamu minta aku lakukan?
What are you talking about now, are you?
Apa yang kamu bicarakan sekarang, kan?
You really didn't know?
Anda benar-benar tidak tahu?
Yeonwoo oppa
Yeonwoo oppa
(Misuk) The principal’s son.
(Misuk) Anak kepala sekolah.
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
That person is the criminal
Orang itu adalah penjahatnya
[surprised gasp] [Soaring music]
[terkejut terkesiap] [Musik yang melonjak]
[Hae-jun groans with difficulty] [Yeonwoo’s heavy breathing]
[Hae-jun mengerang dengan susah payah] [Nafas Yeonwoo yang berat]
[Hae-joon’s sound of strength]
[Suara kekuatan Hae-joon]
[Heavy breathing]
[Nafas berat]
[Hae-jun groans]
[Hae-jun mengerang]
Youngah Yoon [dark music]
Youngah Yoon [musik gelap]
I know where to go
Saya tahu ke mana harus pergi
[Urgent music]
[Musik yang mendesak]
[Sound of falling]
[Suara jatuh]
[Mountain bird crying]
[Burung gunung menangis]
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
[Tense sound effect]
[Efek suara menegangkan]
[Thump] [Passionate music]
[Buk] [Musik yang penuh gairah]
[Sound of whistling wind]
[Suara angin bersiul]
[Puck]
[Keping]
[Soaring music]
[Musik yang melonjak]
[gunshot] [Yeonwoo’s moans]
[tembakan] [erangan Yeonwoo]
[intense music]
[musik yang intens]
(Dongsik) Jooyoung Lee, Kyungae Lee Murder charges against Yoo Beom-ryong and
(Dongsik) Jooyoung Lee, Kyungae Lee Tuduhan pembunuhan terhadap Yoo Beom-ryong dan
About Lee Soon-ae and Yoon Hae-jun on charges of attempted murder
Tentang Lee Soon-ae dan Yoon Hae-jun atas tuduhan percobaan pembunuhan
Yeonwoo Yoon was booked.
Yeonwoo Yoon sudah dipesan.
From now on, to secure evidence We will begin search and seizure.
Mulai sekarang, untuk mengamankan bukti Kami akan memulai pencarian dan penyitaan.
(Detective) Let’s go
(Detektif) Ayo pergi
(Dongsik) Hey, Chairman. Are you okay?
(Dongsik) Hei, Ketua. Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
[Byunggu’s labored breathing]
[Nafas Byunggu yang sesak]
No, this What happened? uh?
Tidak, ini Apa yang terjadi? eh?
(Byung-gu) What kind of situation is this? Dongsik, huh?
(Byung-gu) Situasi macam apa ini? Dongsik ya?
Teacher Hae-jun Yoon He is currently transported to the hospital.
Guru Hae-jun Yoon Dia saat ini diangkut ke rumah sakit.
I'm still unconscious
Aku masih tidak sadarkan diri
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
[surprised gasp]
[terkejut terkesiap]
Hae-jun
Hae-jun
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon
[Crying] No, this is What on earth is this...
[Menangis] Tidak, ini Apa-apaan ini...
Hae-jun
Hae-jun
[Byung-gu’s crying sound]
[Suara tangisan Byung-gu]
[Byunggu sobs]
[Byunggu terisak]
Wow, Hae-jun
Wow, Hae Jun
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
Now the culprit is
Sekarang pelakunya adalah
What happens?
Apa yang terjadi?
I completed my research well.
Saya menyelesaikan penelitian saya dengan baik.
They should be punished properly.
Mereka harus dihukum dengan setimpal.
(Dongsik) That’s it
(Dongsik) Itu saja
This is probably what Teacher Hae-jun Yoon also wants.
This is probably what Teacher Hae-jun Yoon also wants.
(Yoonyoung) As long as I get caught I thought it would all end
(Yoonyoung) Selama aku tertangkap Saya pikir semuanya akan berakhir
without any guilt
tanpa rasa bersalah
people who died horribly
orang yang meninggal secara mengenaskan
Paying the full price for those sins I don't know if it's possible
Membayar harga penuh untuk dosa-dosa itu Saya tidak tahu apakah itu mungkin
Still...
Tetap saja...
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
But now to that person
Tapi sekarang untuk orang itu
maybe it never ends I feel like it's happened
mungkin itu tidak akan pernah berakhir Saya merasa hal itu telah terjadi
I'm so scared of that
Aku sangat takut akan hal itu
How could that person Can you give me this answer?
Bagaimana bisa orang itu Bisakah Anda memberi saya jawaban ini?
That's so pitiful
Itu sangat menyedihkan
[sniffling]
[mendengus]
(Byung-gu) That kid
(Byung-gu) Anak itu
That kid really did it You mean they made it like that?
Anak itu benar-benar melakukannya Maksudmu mereka membuatnya seperti itu?
[Byunggu’s trembling breathing]
[Nafas Byunggu yang gemetar]
When Yeonwoo returns I personally picked you up at the airport.
Saat Yeonwoo kembali Saya pribadi menjemput Anda di bandara.
no, in my car After driving for over four hours round trip, I
tidak, di mobilku Setelah berkendara selama lebih dari empat jam pulang pergi, saya
He said he came back with that kid next to him.
Dia bilang dia kembali dengan anak di sebelahnya.
And at that time There was already a dead person in town
Dan pada saat itu Sudah ada orang mati di kota
There was chaos on my way back
Terjadi kekacauan dalam perjalanan kembali
I saw it with that kid. But how...
Aku melihatnya dengan anak itu. Tapi bagaimana...
Chairman
Ketua
Have you checked your passport?
Sudahkah Anda memeriksa paspor Anda?
passport?
paspor?
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
(Dongsik) Yeonwoo is in this village The first time I came
(Dongsik) Yeonwoo ada di desa ini Pertama kali saya datang
More than the Chairman knows It was much earlier
Lebih dari yang diketahui Ketua Itu jauh lebih awal
I was suspicious from the beginning The reason why it couldn't be done
Saya curiga sejak awal Alasan mengapa hal itu tidak bisa dilakukan
That's why
Itu sebabnya
Yeonwoo
Yeonwoo
He fooled everyone from the beginning.
Dia membodohi semua orang sejak awal.
Even the day I returned to this village.
Bahkan pada hari aku kembali ke desa ini.
[Slight moan]
[Sedikit mengerang]
[Yeonwoo’s sound of pain]
[Suara kesakitan Yeonwoo]
[Dongsik sighs]
[Dongsik menghela nafas]
(Dongsik) When, where, and how Did you commit a crime?
(Dongsik) Kapan, dimana, dan bagaimana Apakah Anda melakukan kejahatan?
Now say it with your own mouth
Sekarang katakan dengan mulutmu sendiri
It hurts
Itu menyakitkan
Don't be fooled, Mr. Lee.
Jangan tertipu, Tuan Lee.
(Dongsik) Speak straight!
(Dongsik) Bicaralah dengan jujur!
(Yeonwoo) It hurts
(Yeonwoo) Sakit
This arm that you shot
Lengan yang kamu tembak ini
Are you saying it hurts?
Apakah kamu mengatakan itu menyakitkan?
I guess I need some treatment I think I should get it
Sepertinya aku perlu perawatan Saya pikir saya harus mendapatkannya
my father Can you please call me?
ayahku Bisakah Anda menelepon saya?
(Dongsik) You now Do you know where this is?
(Dongsik) Kamu sekarang Tahukah kamu dimana ini?
you are here You don’t know why I came in!
kamu di sini Anda tidak tahu mengapa saya masuk!
I'm not sure
Saya tidak yakin
Could it be that you are Could you explain?
Mungkinkah itu kamu Bisakah Anda menjelaskannya?
what?
Apa?
It's like evidence. [dark music]
Ini seperti bukti. [musik gelap]
If you could at least show me something like that...
If you could at least show me something like that...
Why?
Mengapa?
Nothing like that?
Tidak ada yang seperti itu?
[light laughter]
[tertawa ringan]
By now, my house, my room
Saat ini, rumahku, kamarku
You've probably already searched everything.
Anda mungkin sudah mencari semuanya.
But what's missing?
Tapi apa yang hilang?
[Yeonwoo laughs]
[Yeonwoo tertawa]
Of course not
Tentu saja tidak
Because I didn't do that
Karena saya tidak melakukan itu
Right?
Benar?
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
[Sound of door opening and closing]
[Suara pintu dibuka dan ditutup]
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
Are you okay?
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
(Yoonyoung) Can you come to your senses?
(Yoonyoung) Bisakah kamu sadar?
What happened to the culprit?
Apa yang terjadi dengan pelakunya?
It's over, now
Sudah berakhir, sekarang
(Yoon Young) Detective Baek Dong-sik took him away. I'm investigating
(Yoon Young) Detektif Baek Dong-sik membawanya pergi. Saya sedang menyelidiki
[Haejun sighs]
[Haejun menghela nafas]
Are you going to keep avoiding my eyes?
Apakah kamu akan terus menghindari mataku?
[Calm music]
[Musik yang tenang]
I'm sorry
aku minta maaf
(Haejun) I made you lose your family I hurt you
(Haejun) Aku membuatmu kehilangan keluargamu aku menyakitimu
He was my father
Dia adalah ayahku
I too from that horrible person. I'm the one who started it
Saya juga dari orang yang mengerikan itu. Akulah yang memulainya
That terrible person I hurt you too
Orang yang mengerikan itu aku juga menyakitimu
(Yoonyoung) But why are you Are you sorry?
(Yoonyoung) Tapi kenapa kamu Apakah kamu menyesal?
you and me
kamu dan aku
What our family had to go through In all of this
Apa yang keluarga kami harus lalui Dalam semua ini
It's not your fault at all
Itu sama sekali bukan salahmu
So never say things like this again
Jadi jangan pernah mengatakan hal seperti ini lagi
Don't even think like this
Jangan berpikir seperti ini
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
no matter where you started
tidak peduli dari mana Anda memulai
Nothing changes for me
Tidak ada yang berubah bagi saya
thank you for waking me up
terima kasih sudah membangunkanku
[Grass bug crying]
[Serangga rumput menangis]
(Cheongah) Chairman
(Cheongah) Ketua
[secret music]
[musik rahasia]
(Dongsik) I’m 100% emotionally
(Dongsik) Aku 100% emosional
We fell into the trap we made
Kami jatuh ke dalam perangkap yang kami buat
That I exist again As soon as I found out, I ran away.
Bahwa aku ada lagi Begitu saya mengetahuinya, saya lari.
even your car Stealing and running away
bahkan mobilmu Mencuri dan melarikan diri
Well, that's how it was made.
Nah, begitulah cara pembuatannya.
I saw that you even lied about your entry date.
Saya melihat Anda bahkan berbohong tentang tanggal masuk Anda.
Something questionable I don't think it's just one or two things.
Sesuatu yang dipertanyakan Menurutku itu bukan hanya satu atau dua hal.
But just
Tapi adil
There isn't a single solid evidence
Tidak ada satu pun bukti kuat
Yeonwoo Does that guy know that too? It's just leisure
Yeonwoo Apakah pria itu juga mengetahuinya? Itu hanya waktu luang
Probably enough to not be noticed Looks like they put it away properly.
Mungkin cukup untuk tidak diperhatikan Sepertinya mereka menyimpannya dengan benar.
When I see you even mentioning evidence to me,
Ketika saya melihat Anda menyebutkan bukti kepada saya,
(Haejun) How’s your handwriting?
(Haejun) Bagaimana tulisan tanganmu?
Is it the same as what was written on the note? Have you checked?
Apakah sama dengan yang tertulis di catatan itu? Sudahkah Anda memeriksanya?
What is this?
Apa ini?
(Cheongah) In the meantime
(Cheongah) Sementara itu
Yeonwoo said to me in America
Yeonwoo berkata kepadaku di Amerika
They sent it to me every week These are letters
Mereka mengirimkannya kepada saya setiap minggu Ini adalah surat
It's something that only I have
Itu adalah sesuatu yang hanya aku miliki
[rustling sound]
[suara gemerisik]
This is
Ini adalah
It’s different from the Yeonwoo handwriting I know.
Ini berbeda dengan tulisan tangan Yeonwoo yang kukenal.
Because only I know the writing.
Karena hanya saya yang tahu tulisannya.
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
in this world
di dunia ini
Only I know specifically
Hanya saya yang tahu secara spesifik
Because it was written like that.
Karena ditulis seperti itu.
Maybe now
Mungkin sekarang
Other people will recognize it too.
Orang lain juga akan mengenalinya.
The note the criminal left to the victims
Catatan yang ditinggalkan penjahat kepada para korban
And the words written there
Dan kata-kata yang tertulis di sana
Because it's the same [Soaring music]
Karena itu sama [Musik yang melonjak]
(Yoonyoung) The handwriting is
(Yoonyoung) Tulisan tangannya adalah
Easy to hide It's not something you can hide.
Mudah disembunyikan Itu bukan sesuatu yang bisa Anda sembunyikan.
(Dongsik) So it’s frustrating.
(Dongsik) Jadi itu membuat frustrasi.
Just like when Go Min-su
Sama seperti saat Go Min-su
Written in usual handwriting If there is anything
Ditulis dengan tulisan tangan biasa Jika ada sesuatu
We can compare them with each other.
Kita bisa membandingkannya satu sama lain.
No matter how much I search, I can't find it, so
Tidak peduli seberapa banyak aku mencari, aku tidak dapat menemukannya, jadi
Then the news ended the woman you came looking for
Kemudian beritanya berakhir wanita yang kamu cari
Bongbong Cafe CEO
CEO Kafe Bongbong
Did she tell you? Yeonwoo is the culprit
Apakah dia memberitahumu? Yeonwoo adalah pelakunya
Something that comes from there I thought there might be
Sesuatu yang berasal dari sana Saya pikir mungkin ada
I'm trying hard to find it.
Aku berusaha keras untuk menemukannya.
Where did it disappear after reaching the coffee shop?
Where did it disappear after reaching the coffee shop?
My whereabouts are unknown.
Keberadaan saya tidak diketahui.
He's probably left town by now.
Dia mungkin sudah meninggalkan kota sekarang.
Because I was the one who wanted to do that.
Karena akulah yang ingin melakukan itu.
(Byung-gu) No, what is that...
(Byung-gu) Tidak, apa itu...
(Cheongah) Unlike other people
(Cheongah) Tidak seperti orang lain
I will write something special for you
Aku akan menulis sesuatu yang spesial untukmu
Only when you write to me
Hanya ketika Anda menulis kepada saya
I said I would write with my other hand.
Aku bilang aku akan menulis dengan tanganku yang lain.
[Meaningful music] I thought it was romantic.
[Musik yang bermakna] Menurutku itu romantis.
Thinking like that Because I’m a person who knows how to do it
Berpikir seperti itu Karena saya adalah orang yang tahu bagaimana melakukannya
It was better
Itu lebih baik
But one day
Tapi suatu hari
Detectives came and came
Detektif datang dan datang
in a matchbox I showed you the note.
dalam kotak korek api Aku sudah menunjukkan kepadamu catatan itu.
Because it’s a matchbox from our coffee shop.
Karena itu kotak korek api dari kedai kopi kami.
If you are a regular customer He said he might recognize me
Jika Anda adalah pelanggan tetap Dia bilang dia mungkin mengenaliku
Of course I recognized it at a glance.
Tentu saja saya langsung mengenalinya.
Because it was a handwriting that only I knew
Karena itu adalah tulisan tangan yang hanya aku yang tahu
Then
Lalu
Why didn't you tell me right then?
Kenapa kamu tidak memberitahuku saat itu juga?
Are you...
Apakah kamu...
[surprised gasp]
[terkejut terkesiap]
(Cheongah) I wanted to run away
(Cheongah) Saya ingin melarikan diri
just
hanya
I just wanted to run away
Saya hanya ingin melarikan diri
I really meant to do that
Aku sungguh bermaksud melakukan itu
Haejun Yoon
Haejun Yoon
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
To that person Because I told it off...
Kepada orang itu Karena aku sudah mengatakannya...
But there will be no evidence
Tapi tidak akan ada bukti
Yeonwoo is a smart person.
Yeonwoo adalah orang yang cerdas.
Probably a mistake I wouldn't have done it
Mungkin sebuah kesalahan Saya tidak akan melakukannya
Except this
Kecuali ini
So...
Jadi...
(Byung-gu) You
(Byung-gu) Kamu
What is the real reason you came to see me?
Apa alasan sebenarnya kamu datang menemuiku?
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
(Yoonyoung) Me, detective.
(Yoonyoung) Aku, detektif.
That...
Itu...
I'm the owner of Bongbong Cafe.
Saya pemilik Kafe Bongbong.
If you're looking for it, I Is there anything I can do to help?
Jika kamu mencarinya, aku Apakah ada yang bisa saya lakukan untuk membantu?
uh?
eh?
I think he's an important person.
Menurutku dia orang penting.
(Yoonyoung) Now to us too But especially
(Yoonyoung) Sekarang untuk kita juga Tapi khususnya
More for that person
Lebih untuk orang itu
[Surprise] No way...
[Kejutan] Tidak mungkin...
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
(Yoonyoung) If you left the village
(Yoonyoung) Jika kamu meninggalkan desa
It may have gone through the car owner's house.
Mungkin sudah melewati rumah pemilik mobil.
Through my maternal grandfather Is there anything I can find out?
Melalui kakek dari pihak ibu saya Apakah ada sesuatu yang bisa saya temukan?
I'll go see it
Aku akan pergi melihatnya
Thank you, Yoon Young-a
Terima kasih, Yoon Young-a
[Meaningful music] (Hyungman) I saw it if you were the owner of Bongbong Cafe.
[Musik yang bermakna] (Hyungman) Saya melihatnya jika Anda adalah pemilik Bongbong Cafe.
In front of my husband’s house I sat alone for a long time
Di depan rumah suamiku Saya duduk sendirian untuk waktu yang lama
Because the woman is sitting alone like that Because my heart is written
Karena wanita itu duduk sendirian seperti itu Karena hatiku tertulis
I also sat a little longer Just to watch the bus ride
Saya juga duduk lebih lama Hanya untuk menonton perjalanan bus
Then where did it go Did you see what bus I was on?
Lalu kemana perginya Apakah kamu melihat bus apa yang aku naiki?
[Sighing] Oh, I don’t know.
[Menghela nafas] Oh, aku tidak tahu.
I don't really remember that...
Aku tidak begitu ingat itu...
[Hyungman sighs]
[Hyungman menghela nafas]
(Yoonyoung) Thank you
(Yoonyoung) Terima kasih
Are you okay?
Apakah kamu baik-baik saja?
(Hyungman) What?
(Hyungman) Apa?
Because of the chairman’s son?
Karena putra ketua?
Tsk [Hyungman sighs]
Ck [Hyungman menghela nafas]
I honestly still can't believe it.
Sejujurnya aku masih tidak percaya.
Chairman
Ketua
He’s such a good person.
Dia orang yang baik.
A child born from such a good person
Seorang anak yang lahir dari orang baik
How...
Bagaimana...
Tsk, but on the other hand
Ck, tapi di sisi lain
If that guy was really the culprit I also have a heart to say
Jika orang itu benar-benar pelakunya Aku juga punya hati untuk mengatakannya
Why?
Mengapa?
If that's the case, you've already been caught.
Jika itu masalahnya, Anda sudah tertangkap.
(Hyungman) It’s all over.
(Hyungman) Semuanya sudah berakhir.
other people
orang lain
Pain like our children You don’t have to go through this.
Sakit seperti anak-anak kita Anda tidak harus melalui ini.
[Sad music] Any person in the world
[Musik sedih] Siapa pun di dunia
no family
tidak ada keluarga
[Hyungman sighs]
[Hyungman menghela nafas]
This kind of feeling
Perasaan seperti ini
Because I hope you don’t feel it
Karena saya harap Anda tidak merasakannya
To Teacher Yoon
Kepada Guru Yoon
Thank you so much tell me again
Terima kasih banyak beritahu aku lagi
Thank you for catching me
Terima kasih telah menangkapku
Thank you so much for finishing it.
Terima kasih banyak telah menyelesaikannya.
yes
ya
[dark music] [sigh]
[musik gelap] [menghela nafas]
(Hae-jun) There is no evidence?
(Hae-jun) Tidak ada bukti?
Why?
Mengapa?
The handwriting I remember from my father is...
Tulisan tangan yang saya ingat dari ayah saya adalah...
There is no
Tidak ada
I remember seeing my father’s handwriting
Saya ingat melihat tulisan tangan ayah saya
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
[Excited breathing]
[Nafas bersemangat]
(Little Haejun) Grandpa
(Haejun Kecil) Kakek
What is this?
Apa ini?
I said I know how to read now.
Saya bilang saya tahu cara membaca sekarang.
Dad told me I sent you a letter, Grandpa.
Ayah memberitahuku Aku mengirimimu surat, Kakek.
[Byunggu’s heavy breathing]
[Napas berat Byunggu]
Such a horrible son of a bitch.
Bajingan yang mengerikan.
[Soaring music]
[Musik yang melonjak]
I knew it
Saya mengetahuinya
I knew it all back then too
Aku juga mengetahui semuanya saat itu
[Grass bug crying]
[Serangga rumput menangis]
[Crackling sound]
[Suara berderak]
[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon
[Emphasized sound effect]
[Efek suara yang ditekankan]
How do you...
Bagaimana kamu...
(Haejun) What are you doing now?
(Haejun) Apa yang kamu lakukan sekarang?
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon, that, I...
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon, itu, aku...
(Haejun) The criminal’s handwriting is written on it It's evidence.
(Haejun) Tulisan tangan penjahat tertulis di sana Itu bukti.
Why?
Mengapa?
Are you going to burn it all down?
Apakah kamu akan membakar semuanya?
(Byung-gu) I know
(Byung-gu) Aku tahu
I know it's crazy
Aku tahu ini gila
It's something that deserves punishment I know everything, but
Itu adalah sesuatu yang patut mendapat hukuman Aku tahu segalanya, tapi
But what?
Tapi apa?
This remains Because your life is at stake
Ini tetap ada Karena nyawamu dipertaruhkan
(Byunggu) Because your future depends on it I couldn't help it
(Byunggu) Karena masa depanmu bergantung padanya Saya tidak bisa menahannya
This is for me It was the best choice for you
Ini untukku Itu adalah pilihan terbaik untuk Anda
Right now in your mother's womb That kid, you
Saat ini di dalam rahim ibumu Anak itu, kamu
killed three people To be born and live as the child of a murderer
membunuh tiga orang Untuk dilahirkan dan hidup sebagai anak seorang pembunuh
How, how can I Can you just wait and see?
Bagaimana, bagaimana aku bisa Bisakah kamu menunggu dan melihat saja?
Hae-jun
Hae-jun
I will take all the punishment
Saya akan menerima semua hukumannya
Even if I fall into hell Because I will take all the punishment
Bahkan jika aku jatuh ke neraka Karena aku akan menanggung semua hukumannya
As if you don't know anything Just like everyone else
Seolah-olah Anda tidak tahu apa-apa Sama seperti orang lain
Can't I just live a normal life? huh?
Tidak bisakah aku menjalani kehidupan normal saja? Hah?
That guy will never come to you again Don't do terrible things
Orang itu tidak akan pernah mendatangimu lagi Jangan melakukan hal-hal buruk
I'll stop everything, Hae-jun.
Aku akan menghentikan semuanya, Hae-jun.
It was like this back then too
Dulu juga seperti ini
Even then
Meski begitu
Covering everything, including you
Meliputi segalanya, termasuk Anda
Everything was just buried
Semuanya terkubur begitu saja
If you do this
Jika Anda melakukan ini
After covering it up like this
Setelah menutupinya seperti ini
I do as you wish Do you think you can live well?
Saya melakukan apa yang Anda inginkan Apakah kamu pikir kamu bisa hidup dengan baik?
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
for my future Don't make excuses like that
untuk masa depanku Jangan membuat alasan seperti itu
Even if everything is covered I can't even live comfortably
Sekalipun semuanya tertutup Aku bahkan tidak bisa hidup dengan nyaman
Even his son's son I lived while ignoring
Bahkan anak dari anaknya Saya hidup sambil mengabaikan
Because it's your life
Karena itu hidupmu
(Haejun) For life
(Haejun) Seumur hidup
Just looking at your cold back Because what I lived was my life
Hanya melihat punggungmu yang dingin Karena apa yang saya jalani adalah hidup saya
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
(Byung-gu) No, no! no, no
(Byung-gu) Tidak, tidak! tidak, tidak
Even though I know that future
Meskipun aku tahu masa depan itu
Are you going to make this choice?
Apakah Anda akan membuat pilihan ini?
[Sobbing]
[Menangis]
[shaking breathing]
[napas gemetar]
[Rough breathing]
[Nafas kasar]
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
Direct bus from Chabujip I heard you even saw it burning.
Bus langsung dari Chabujip Aku dengar kamu bahkan melihatnya terbakar.
As far as that goes...
Sejauh itu...
(Dongsik) Oh, it’s okay
(Dongsik) Oh, tidak apa-apa
You don't have to look anymore
Anda tidak perlu melihat lagi
Why?
Mengapa?
Teacher Yoon Hae-jun just visited.
Guru Yoon Hae-jun baru saja berkunjung.
What do you mean? Why does someone need to be in the hospital right now?
Apa maksudmu? Mengapa seseorang perlu berada di rumah sakit saat ini?
(Dongsik) Yeonwoo
(Dongsik) Yeonwoo
Written in the criminal's handwriting I gave the evidence and left.
Ditulis dengan tulisan tangan penjahat Saya memberikan bukti dan pergi.
You found evidence, he?
Anda menemukan bukti, dia?
(Dongsik) Yes, this is enough I think I can finish it
(Dongsik) Ya, ini sudah cukup Saya pikir saya bisa menyelesaikannya
Thanks to you this time
Terima kasih padamu kali ini
I think I can get it right
Saya pikir saya bisa melakukannya dengan benar
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
Don't you ask me where I've been?
Tidakkah kamu bertanya kemana saja aku pergi?
I heard it all
Saya mendengar semuanya
I'm okay now Can’t I be discharged from the hospital?
Saya baik-baik saja sekarang Tidak bisakah saya keluar dari rumah sakit?
Of course not, not yet.
Tentu saja belum, belum.
I want to go home now
Saya ingin pulang sekarang
[Calm music]
[Musik yang tenang]
(Yoonyoung) I’ll make sure to say thank you. Grandfather
(Yoonyoung) Aku pasti akan mengucapkan terima kasih. Kakek
Earlier, in front of the driver’s house
Tadi, di depan rumah sopir
The owner of Bongbong Cafe I heard you ran into each other
Pemilik Kafe Bongbong Saya mendengar Anda bertemu satu sama lain
What bus are you planning on taking?
Bus apa yang ingin kamu naiki?
Even if a car comes in I don't want to ride
Bahkan jika ada mobil masuk Saya tidak ingin berkendara
keep doing something He said he was just looking down.
terus melakukan sesuatu Dia bilang dia hanya melihat ke bawah.
(Hyungman) Where are you going far away?
(Hyungman) Kemana kamu akan pergi jauh?
yes
ya
Oh my, this is the first car to come. It's still far away, but at this early morning...
Ya ampun, ini mobil pertama yang datang. Memang masih jauh, tapi pagi-pagi begini...
(Hyungman) Well, then I'll leave the door open
(Hyungman) Kalau begitu Aku akan membiarkan pintunya terbuka
I'm inside
aku di dalam
It's okay
Tidak apa-apa
Oh, I'm fine too
Oh, aku juga baik-baik saja
After losing my daughter The world is just scary and arrogant
Setelah kehilangan putriku Dunia ini menakutkan dan sombong
Still, I'm glad the culprit was caught.
Tetap saja, aku senang pelakunya tertangkap.
(Hyungman) Right?
(Hyungman) Benar?
yes
Ya
(Hyungman) Oh my, it’s so pretty.
(Hyungman) Ya ampun, cantik sekali.
(Yoonyoung) For a long time, just baby socks I fiddled with it and then
(Yoonyoung) Untuk waktu yang lama, hanya kaus kaki bayi Aku mengutak-atiknya lalu
They said you barely left.
Mereka bilang kamu baru saja pergi.
is your mother
adalah ibumu
Did you know?
Tahukah kamu?
Where did you go? Would you like to find out more?
Kemana kamu pergi? Apakah Anda ingin mengetahui lebih lanjut?
No
Tidak
It's okay, I
Tidak apa-apa, aku
[Exciting music]
[Musik yang menarik]
[Birdsong]
[Kicau Burung]
(Reporter Kim) Woojeong-ri serial murder case The suspect was arrested
(Reporter Kim) Kasus pembunuhan berantai Woojeong-ri Tersangka ditangkap
Please give me a briefing on the current situation.
Tolong beri saya pengarahan tentang situasi saat ini.
(Dongsik) Ah...
(Dongsik) Ah...
yes
ya
Since last May, our police
Sejak Mei lalu, polisi kita
Happened in Ujeong-ri Village three murders and
Terjadi di Desa Ujeong-ri tiga pembunuhan dan
two attempted murder cases to arrest a suspect
dua kasus percobaan pembunuhan untuk menangkap tersangka
Successful
Berhasil
Suspect Mr. Yoon Having lived abroad for a long time
Tersangka Tuan Yoon Sudah lama tinggal di luar negeri
As an international student in his mid-20s
Sebagai siswa internasional berusia pertengahan 20-an
Arrest warrant for charges As issued
Surat perintah penangkapan atas tuduhan Seperti yang dikeluarkan
Arrest Mr. Yoon
Tangkap Tuan Yoon
The motive and actions of the crime After a thorough investigation
Motif dan tindakan kejahatan Setelah penyelidikan menyeluruh
We plan to send it to the prosecution.
Kami berencana mengirimkannya ke kejaksaan.
(Resident 1) Oh my goodness
(Warga 1) Ya ampun
The chairman is very The only son who raised Geumji Ok-yeop, huh?
Ketua sangat Satu-satunya anak laki-laki yang membesarkan Geumji Ok-yeop ya?
Oh, that guy You mean he was the real culprit?
Oh, pria itu Maksudmu dia pelaku sebenarnya?
Oh my, you're smart I have a lot of money at home
Ya ampun, kamu pintar Saya punya banyak uang di rumah
A child who has a lot What is lacking and what is lacking?
Seorang anak yang mempunyai banyak hal Apa yang kurang dan apa yang kurang?
Why would you do such a terrible thing? Wow, tsk [Resident 1 sighs]
Mengapa kamu melakukan hal yang begitu buruk? Wah, ck [Warga 1 menghela nafas]
(Hyungman) If it’s not enough and you’re not good enough Can I do that?
(Hyungman) Jika itu tidak cukup dan kamu tidak cukup baik Bisakah saya melakukan itu?
(Resident 2) Child, Sunae’s father Well, that's not it...
(Warga 2) Anak, ayah Sunae Yah, bukan itu...
What I raised preciously Same goes for my daughter.
Apa yang saya besarkan dengan sangat berharga Hal yang sama berlaku untuk putri saya.
(Hyungman) Anyway, those damn words, oh my
(Hyungman) Pokoknya, kata-kata sialan itu, astaga
(Resident 2) Oh, man, man... [People mutter]
(Warga 2) Aduh, bung... [Orang-orang bergumam]
[Grunting sound] [sigh]
[Suara mendengus] [menghela nafas]
(Anchor on TV) Over a month Suspect in the Ujeong-ri serial murder case
(Penyiar di TV) Lebih dari sebulan Tersangka kasus pembunuhan berantai Ujeong-ri
finally arrested
akhirnya ditangkap
The nightmare of the anxious villagers It's finally over
Mimpi buruk penduduk desa yang cemas Ini akhirnya berakhir
[Residents are noisy] Reporter Kim Sang-oh reports.
[Warga berisik] Reporter Kim Sang-oh melaporkan.
(Reporter Kim on TV) Over the past month occurred in succession
(Reporter Kim di TV) Selama sebulan terakhir terjadi secara berturut-turut
Suspect in Ujeong-ri murder case Mr. Yoon was arrested.
Tersangka dalam kasus pembunuhan Ujeong-ri Tuan Yoon ditangkap.
come into the police station [Noisy]
datang ke kantor polisi [Berisik]
Mr. Yoon is a member of the press team. Being showered with cameras
Tuan Yoon adalah anggota tim pers. Dihujani kamera
Moved to the police interrogation room
Pindah ke ruang interogasi polisi
Suspect Mr. Yoon He denied the murder charge, but
Tersangka Tuan Yoon Dia membantah tuduhan pembunuhan itu, tapi
Police found at the scene of the murder The handwriting of the note and
Polisi ditemukan di lokasi pembunuhan Tulisan tangan catatan dan
Mr. Yoon’s handwriting showing agreement
Tulisan tangan Tuan Yoon menunjukkan persetujuan
They said they had secured evidence. [Calm music]
Mereka mengaku sudah mengamankan barang bukti. [Musik yang tenang]
[Grass bug crying]
[Serangga rumput menangis]
(Haejun) Now for real I think it's all over
(Haejun) Sekarang sebenarnya Saya pikir semuanya sudah berakhir
I caught the culprit too
Aku juga menangkap pelakunya
What I can do here I think I'm done
Apa yang bisa saya lakukan di sini Saya pikir saya sudah selesai
I also fixed the car
Saya juga memperbaiki mobilnya
now
sekarang
We should go back soon
Kita harus segera kembali
Let's leave?
Ayo pergi?
As someone who doesn't exist You can't buy it
Sebagai seseorang yang tidak ada Anda tidak bisa membelinya
We need to check the changed future as well.
Kita juga perlu memeriksa perubahan masa depan.
(Haejun) Father and mother With my family
(Haejun) Ayah dan ibu Dengan keluargaku
Because there has to be time to say hello
Karena harus ada waktu untuk menyapa
Um...
eh...
How about leaving tomorrow night?
Bagaimana kalau berangkat besok malam?
yes
ya
I do that
saya melakukan itu
(Yoonyoung) Do you want it?
(Yoonyoung) Apakah kamu menginginkannya?
(Yeonwoo) I don’t want anyone to see it.
(Yeonwoo) Saya tidak ingin ada yang melihatnya.
Still to my father No contact? yes?
Masih pada ayahku Tidak ada kontak? Ya?
I'll trust you and make room for you
Aku akan mempercayaimu dan memberi ruang untukmu
Let's talk and come out
Mari kita bicara dan keluar
yes
ya
[Fluttering sound]
[Suara berkibar]
[Interesting music]
[Musik yang menarik]
[Heeseop sighs]
[Heeseop menghela nafas]
[Shop owner's exclamation]
[Seruan pemilik toko]
(Store owner) This lucky person is I wondered who it would be
(Pemilik toko) Orang yang beruntung ini Saya bertanya-tanya siapa orangnya
In the end, Hee-seop becomes you?
Pada akhirnya, Hee-seop menjadi dirimu?
I always say I have no money in front of me I walked around drooling
Saya selalu mengatakan saya tidak punya uang di depan saya Aku berjalan sambil ngiler
I hope
saya harap
Received it as a gift from my lover
Menerimanya sebagai hadiah dari kekasihku
(Hee-seop and Yoon-young) Lovers!
(Hee-seop dan Yoon-young) Pecinta!
(Yoonyoung)
(Yoonyoung)
[lively music] (Store owner) No, no.
[musik yang hidup] (Pemilik toko) Tidak, tidak.
(Hee-seop) Oh, this isn’t real.
(Hee-seop) Oh, ini tidak nyata.
- Oh, I won't buy it! - (Store owner) Oh, that's enough.
- Oh, aku tidak akan membelinya! - (Pemilik toko) Oh, sudah cukup.
[Heeseop sighs]
[Heeseop menghela nafas]
(Heeseop) Are you crazy?
(Heeseop) Apakah kamu gila?
What, is 200,000 won a joke?
Apa, 200.000 won itu lelucon?
Why did you do this to me...
Kenapa kamu melakukan ini padaku...
Oh, it's not even your money.
Oh, itu bahkan bukan uangmu.
Did you steal money from your master? this?
Apakah kamu mencuri uang dari tuanmu? ini?
If I get caught, I'll just...
Jika aku tertangkap, aku hanya akan...
(Yoonyoung) Ah! [Yoonyoung sighs]
(Yoonyoung) Ah! [Yoonyoung menghela nafas]
Because I decided to pay it all off later. Stop talking nonsense and come out with something
Karena saya memutuskan untuk melunasi semuanya nanti. Berhentilah bicara omong kosong dan keluarkan sesuatu
It's so loud it's killing me, really, Mr.
Keras sekali, aku hampir mati, sungguh, Tn.
[absurd gasping sound]
[suara terengah-engah yang tidak masuk akal]
(Store owner) Now Now it's really yours
(Pemilik toko) Sekarang Sekarang itu benar-benar milikmu
[Heeseop sighs]
[Heeseop menghela nafas]
yes
ya
[Light elasticity] Thank you, guest.
[Elastisitas ringan] Terima kasih, tamu.
Wow
Wah
[Sound of opening a zipper]
[Suara membuka ritsleting]
[Heeseop’s faint exclamation]
[Seruan samar Heeseop]
[Heeseop clears his cough]
[Heeseop menghilangkan batuknya]
(Heeseop) You can’t believe it
(Heeseop) Kamu tidak bisa mempercayainya
Feeling like you like me...
Merasa seperti kamu menyukaiku...
(Yoonyoung) It’s a bribe.
(Yoonyoung) Itu suap.
[Calm music]
[Musik yang tenang]
In the future too
Di masa depan juga
To my best friend Soonae Be good to me for the rest of your life
Untuk sahabatku Soonae Bersikaplah baik padaku selama sisa hidupmu
Just once in the eyes of pure love If there is something that brings tears to my eyes
Sekali saja di mata cinta yang murni Jika ada sesuatu yang membuat saya menitikkan air mata
I won't just leave it alone
Aku tidak akan membiarkannya begitu saja
[laughter]
[tertawa]
(Hee-seop) Oh, is it a bribe or a threat?
(Hee-seop) Oh, apakah itu suap atau ancaman?
Ah, that's me I'm sure you'll take care of it.
Itu aku Saya yakin Anda akan mengurusnya.
Why are you...
Kenapa kamu...
No matter what difficult things happen
Tidak peduli hal sulit apa pun yang terjadi
never break up Let's stay by each other's side
tidak pernah putus Mari kita tetap berada di sisi satu sama lain
That way I
Dengan cara itu saya
Because we will meet again, you
Karena kita akan bertemu lagi, kamu
Where are you going?
Kemana kamu pergi?
I'll probably see you again soon
Saya mungkin akan segera menemui Anda lagi
A little for you It might take a long time
Sedikit untukmu Ini mungkin memakan waktu lama
Ah, what are you talking about?
Ah, apa yang kamu bicarakan?
Hey, you again Well, doesn’t your head hurt?
Hei, kamu lagi Nah, apakah kepalamu tidak sakit?
(Hee-seop) I don’t think you have a fever?
(Hee-seop) Menurutku kamu tidak demam?
Ah, that's it, go
Ah, itu saja, ayo
Ah, my heart feels a little strange.
Ah, hatiku terasa sedikit aneh.
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
Have a really good time this time, Dad.
Selamat bersenang-senang kali ini, Ayah.
Don't be sick
Jangan sakit
(Yoonyoung) Without any scars
(Yoonyoung) Tanpa bekas luka
Do whatever you want
Lakukan apa pun yang Anda inginkan
(Haejun) Why on earth did you kill me?
(Haejun) Kenapa kamu membunuhku?
I just wanted to ask you that.
Aku hanya ingin menanyakan itu padamu.
Now I'll never know
Sekarang saya tidak akan pernah tahu
A future that could kill me Because it disappeared
Masa depan yang bisa membunuhku Karena menghilang
[dark music]
[musik gelap]
[Sound of strength]
[Suara kekuatan]
[sigh]
[menghela nafas]
[nervous music]
[musik gugup]
[Click]
[Klik]
[laughter]
[tertawa]
It's fun
Itu menyenangkan
[Sound of opening]
[Suara pembukaan]
[intense music]
[musik yang intens]
"Time travel system"
"Sistem perjalanan waktu"
Oh, was that it?
Oh, apakah itu tadi?
You died in my hands too
Kamu juga mati di tanganku
(Yeonwoo) Even if it’s revenge Is this what you came for?
(Yeonwoo) Meskipun itu balas dendam Apakah ini tujuanmu datang?
If you were that curious I should have left it alone
Jika Anda penasaran Seharusnya aku membiarkannya saja
I won't get caught this time either.
Aku juga tidak akan ketahuan kali ini.
So one more time
Jadi sekali lagi
Kill me
Bunuh aku
No matter how far away we lived
Tidak peduli seberapa jauh kita tinggal
To this extent I didn't know there was another face
Sejauh ini Saya tidak tahu ada wajah lain
What?
Apa?
yes conclusive evidence
ya bukti yang meyakinkan
After looking for that love letter
Setelah mencari surat cinta itu
I got curious
Saya jadi penasaran
[secret music]
[musik rahasia]
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon
(Byung-gu) Hae-joon
You're a smart guy, you
Kamu orang yang pintar, kamu
(Haejun) At the scene of the incident
(Haejun) Di lokasi kejadian
Any mistakes You who didn't leave behind
Ada kesalahan Anda yang tidak meninggalkan
why did i miss it
kenapa aku melewatkannya
It can definitely be evidence I would have known
Itu pasti bisa menjadi bukti saya pasti sudah tahu
That woman did it
Wanita itu yang melakukannya
I could have ended everything for you I would have known
Aku bisa saja mengakhiri segalanya untukmu saya pasti sudah tahu
Why did you leave her alone?
Mengapa kamu meninggalkannya sendirian?
Are you even in love?
Apakah kamu bahkan sedang jatuh cinta?
[laughter]
[tertawa]
(Yeonwoo) Really unexpected Are you asking a question?
(Yeonwoo) Benar-benar tidak terduga Apakah Anda mengajukan pertanyaan?
why did you kill
kenapa kamu membunuh
how did you kill it
bagaimana kamu membunuhnya
I thought you were going to ask a question like that.
Saya pikir Anda akan menanyakan pertanyaan seperti itu.
Love?
Cinta?
I did it
Saya melakukannya
I did it, love
Aku berhasil, sayang
can make my dreams come true I thought it was a girl
bisa mewujudkan mimpiku Saya pikir itu seorang gadis
Because I knew she would be different
Karena aku tahu dia akan berbeda
i know
saya tahu
With some terrible woman
Dengan seorang wanita yang mengerikan
(Yeonwoo) I remember What that woman looks like
(Yeonwoo) Saya ingat Seperti apa rupa wanita itu
Most of them looked like they were reading books.
Kebanyakan dari mereka tampak seperti sedang membaca buku.
Not once, not even once
Tidak sekali pun, tidak sekali pun
Me with warm eyes I don't remember looking at you
Aku dengan mata hangat Aku tidak ingat melihatmu
Then finally, when I was seven years old
Lalu akhirnya, ketika saya berumur tujuh tahun
I left home
Saya meninggalkan rumah
No longer someone's mother Have you stopped wanting to live?
Bukan lagi ibu seseorang Apakah Anda sudah berhenti ingin hidup?
me
saya
Should I meet mom?
Haruskah aku bertemu ibu?
(Cheong-ah) Mom?
(Cheong-ah) Bu?
[heavy music] Do you know about mom?
[musik berat] Tahukah kamu tentang ibu?
[Crying sound]
[Suara tangisan]
More than anyone else in the world
Lebih dari siapa pun di dunia
You have to love me unconditionally The person who is abandoned by people
Kamu harus mencintaiku tanpa syarat Orang yang ditinggalkan orang
Do you know that miserable feeling?
Tahukah kamu perasaan menyedihkan itu?
(Yeonwoo) The person who abandoned me While I miss you without speed
(Yeonwoo) Orang yang meninggalkanku Sementara aku merindukanmu tanpa kecepatan
I cried all night and cried again
Saya menangis sepanjang malam dan menangis lagi
I made a promise in that endless pain
Saya membuat janji dalam rasa sakit yang tak berkesudahan itu
'Someday in the future, when I have a son'
'Suatu hari nanti, ketika aku mempunyai seorang putra'
[Laughing] ‘My son’
[Tertawa] ‘Anakku’
'My baby will never 'Don't let them live like me'
'Bayiku tidak akan pernah 'Jangan biarkan mereka hidup seperti saya'
'The person who can love a child more than anyone else 'I met such a woman'
‘Orang yang bisa mencintai seorang anak lebih dari siapapun 'Saya bertemu wanita seperti itu'
‘I have to live happily’
‘Saya harus hidup bahagia’
So we met
Jadi kami bertemu
A woman like that
Wanita seperti itu
that girl
gadis itu
I was an orphan
Saya adalah seorang yatim piatu
I love my family so much I was a girl who wanted to make
Saya sangat mencintai keluarga saya Saya adalah seorang gadis yang ingin membuat
Did you know that we almost did that?
Tahukah Anda bahwa kita hampir melakukan itu?
what?
Apa?
what you wanted to make so much
apa yang sangat ingin kamu hasilkan
perfect happiness, perfect family
kebahagiaan sempurna, keluarga sempurna
do it yourself Do you know that I kicked it away?
lakukan sendiri Tahukah kamu kalau aku mengusirnya?
What is that...
Apa itu...
So I'm glad
Jadi saya senang
From a guy like you
Dari pria sepertimu
my mother That I was able to escape
ibuku Bahwa saya bisa melarikan diri
[Meaningful music]
[Musik yang bermakna]
[laughter]
[tertawa]
You...
kamu...
You can't believe it...
Anda tidak dapat mempercayainya...
[laughter]
[tertawa]
This doesn't make sense
Ini tidak masuk akal
If you were really my son
Jika kamu benar-benar anakku
(Yeonwoo) You to me I can't do it like this...
(Yeonwoo) Kamu untukku Aku tidak bisa melakukannya seperti ini...
no
tidak
How could I kill you?
Bagaimana aku bisa membunuhmu?
Thanks to having a terrible father like you.
Terima kasih memiliki ayah yang buruk sepertimu.
Abandoned from birth let me tell you
Ditinggalkan sejak lahir biarkan aku memberitahumu
The things you've been talking about so far
Hal-hal yang selama ini Anda bicarakan
caught in victim mentality the murderer talks
terjebak dalam mentalitas korban si pembunuh berbicara
It's just self-pity
Itu hanya mengasihani diri sendiri
So, for the rest of my life yes all the times
Jadi, selama sisa hidupku ya sepanjang waktu
Trapped inside and rotting live a painful life
Terjebak di dalam dan membusuk menjalani kehidupan yang menyakitkan
This is you I wanted to make it so much
Ini kamu Saya sangat ingin membuatnya
This is my last request as your son.
Ini permintaan terakhirku sebagai anakmu.
[Moon So-ri]
[Bulan So-ri]
[Soaring music]
[Musik yang melonjak]
[heavy music]
[musik berat]
[Grass bug crying]
[Serangga rumput menangis]
- (Hyungman) Teacher Yoon - (Okja) Ahyu
- (Hyungman) Guru Yoon - (Oke) Ahyu
(Haejun) Ah, yes
(Haejun) Ah, ya
No, why are you here? What's going on?
Tidak, kenapa kamu ada di sini? Apa yang terjadi?
(Hyungman) Oh, then there is nothing?
(Hyungman) Oh, kalau begitu tidak ada apa-apa?
I heard you're moving. That too tonight
Aku dengar kamu akan pindah. Itu juga malam ini
Oh, how Suddenly, without saying a word in advance...
Oh bagaimana caranya Tiba-tiba, tanpa mengucapkan sepatah kata pun sebelumnya...
I'm really sad, yes?
Aku sungguh sedih, ya?
(Haejun) Yes
(Haejun) Ya
(Okja) I’m so sad, teacher.
(Okja) Saya sedih sekali, Guru.
I thought we were family, but somehow...
Kupikir kita adalah keluarga, tapi entah kenapa...
[shocked breathing]
[kaget bernapas]
[Calm music]
[Musik yang tenang]
We're really going to see each other again, aren't we?
Kita benar-benar akan bertemu lagi, bukan?
[Crying] When?
[Menangis] Kapan?
where?
Di mana?
About 34 years later
Sekitar 34 tahun kemudian
at your house
di rumahmu
I really hate you
Aku sangat membencimu
(Soonae) I’d rather just They say I'll never see you again
(Soonae) Aku lebih suka saja Mereka bilang aku tidak akan pernah bertemu denganmu lagi
Don't wait any longer
Jangan menunggu lebih lama lagi
(Yoonyoung) By then
(Yoonyoung) Saat itu
It might look a little different than it does now.
Ini mungkin terlihat sedikit berbeda dibandingkan sekarang.
I really like that face too
Aku juga sangat menyukai wajah itu
[Crying] That face too
[Menangis] Wajah itu juga
I miss you so much
Aku sangat merindukanmu
Because I was able to come here I think it was really fortunate
Karena saya bisa datang ke sini Saya pikir itu sangat beruntung
now
sekarang
Because I was able to meet you now
Karena aku bisa bertemu denganmu sekarang
Now that I can get it back
Sekarang saya bisa mendapatkannya kembali
I feel so fortunate
Saya merasa sangat beruntung
[Soonae’s crying sound]
[Suara tangisan Soonae]
me too
saya juga
I'm so happy to meet you
Saya sangat senang bertemu dengan Anda
It was good
Itu bagus
[Yoonyoung sobs]
[Yoonyoung terisak]
[Two sobbing sounds]
[Dua suara isak tangis]
thank you
terima kasih
(Hyungman) Thank you so much Mr. Yoon
(Hyungman) Terima kasih banyak Tuan Yoon
For being our neighbors
Karena menjadi tetangga kita
Thank you so much, Mr. Yoon.
Terima kasih banyak, Tuan Yoon.
Ah, yes
Ya, ya
(Haejun) Thank you For saying so
(Haejun) Terima kasih Karena mengatakan demikian
Wow
Wah
(Obok) For helping my older sisters Thank you so much, teacher.
(Obok) Untuk membantu kakak perempuanku Terima kasih banyak, guru.
(Haejun) Yes
(Haejun) Ya
(Okja) Where are you going? Can you please tell me?
(Okja) Mau kemana? Bisakah kamu memberitahuku?
‘Where are you probably now?’ so that you know
'Di mana kamu mungkin sekarang?' agar kamu tahu
At least somewhere
Setidaknya di suatu tempat
It's a bit far away.
Itu agak jauh.
(Haejun) Stay healthy for a long time
(Haejun) Tetap sehat untuk waktu yang lama
I will definitely come to see you
Saya pasti akan datang menemui Anda
(Yoonyoung) We are really leaving, we are leaving
(Yoonyoung) Kami benar-benar pergi, kami akan pergi
(Haejun) That’s right
(Haejun) Itu benar
It's been a while since I'm going to travel back in time
Sudah lama sejak saya melakukan perjalanan kembali ke masa lalu
I'm a little nervous
Saya sedikit gugup
Aren’t you sad?
Apakah kamu tidak sedih?
What is it?
Apa itu?
Just leaving without saying goodbye
Pergi begitu saja tanpa pamit
(Yoonyoung) With your grandfather To my mother
(Yoonyoung) Dengan kakekmu Untuk ibuku
Especially my mother goes here It might really be the last time
Terutama ibuku yang pergi ke sini Ini mungkin yang terakhir kalinya
To see those people I didn't even come
Untuk melihat orang-orang itu Aku bahkan tidak datang
If you do this, you've seen a lot.
Jika Anda melakukan ini, Anda telah melihat banyak hal.
It's enough
Itu sudah cukup
What are you going to do first when you get back?
Apa yang akan kamu lakukan pertama kali ketika kamu kembali?
(Haejun) What do you want to do?
(Haejun) Apa yang ingin kamu lakukan?
(Yoonyoung) Iced Caramel Macchiato Let’s drink something super sweet.
(Yoonyoung) Es Karamel Macchiato Ayo minum sesuatu yang super manis.
If you eat it with salt bread, Do you know how delicious it is?
Jika Anda memakannya dengan roti asin, Tahukah kamu betapa lezatnya itu?
(Haejun) As expected, that guy’s sweet salty salty salty
(Haejun) Benar saja, pria itu manis, asin, asin
[Both laugh]
[Keduanya tertawa]
[Gear operation sound]
[Suara pengoperasian roda gigi]
[Yoonyoung’s nervous breathing]
[Nafas Yoonyoung yang gugup]
[Yoonyoung sighs]
[Yoonyoung menghela nafas]
(Yoonyoung) I’m really a bit nervous.
(Yoonyoung) Aku benar-benar sedikit gugup.
don't worry
jangan khawatir
It's over in the blink of an eye
Ini berakhir dalam sekejap mata
(Haejun) As long as you pass through that tunnel,
(Haejun) Selama kamu melewati terowongan itu,
Like a lie, it’s our home ground
Seperti sebuah kebohongan, ini adalah rumah kami
It will arrive in 2021
Itu akan tiba pada tahun 2021
[deep breath]
[napas dalam-dalam]
Okay, let's go.
Oke, ayo pergi.
[Nervous breathing]
[Nafas gugup]
[Dreamy music]
[Musik yang indah]
[Soaring music]
[Musik yang melonjak]
[Music cuts out]
[Musik berhenti]
Have you arrived?
Apakah kamu sudah sampai?
(Yoonyoung) Have you arrived?
(Yoonyoung) Apakah kamu sudah sampai?
Is it 21?
Apakah ini tanggal 21?
It’s smoother than you think, isn’t it?
Ini lebih mulus dari yang Anda kira, bukan?
(Haejun) It’s been a while since I came here so I’m confused.
(Haejun) Sudah lama sejak saya datang ke sini jadi saya bingung.
Is that right, 2021?
Betulkah, 2021?
Or is it not possible?
Atau tidak mungkin?
[The sound of rustling gets closer]
[Suara gemerisik semakin dekat]
- (Chief) Teacher Yoon! - (Haejun) Ah, yes, yes
- (Kepala) Guru Yoon! - (Haejun) Ah, ya, ya
(Chief) Hey, Teacher Yoon!
(Ketua) Hei, Guru Yoon!
[Sound of clanking tiller]
[Suara anakan berdenting]
I didn't say anchor. In 21?
Saya tidak mengatakan jangkar. Di tahun 21?
[Rhythmic music]
[Musik berirama]
[Haejun sighs]
[Haejun menghela nafas]
(Haejun) June 14, 1987 10:40 PM
(Haejun) 14 Juni 1987 22:40
we are here After finishing everything, I tried to leave, but
kita di sini Setelah menyelesaikan semuanya, aku mencoba pergi, tapi
still remained here
masih tetap di sini
(Yoonyoung) Maybe we will be together forever
(Yoonyoung) Mungkin kita akan bersama selamanya
I might be trapped here It was fate
Saya mungkin terjebak di sini Itu adalah takdir
Subtitle: Jang Se-ri
Subtitle: Jang Se-ri